(忆往昔)
利维坦
Leviathans.
迪克要来了
Dick is coming.
正如我一直说的那样
Well, it's like I always say ...
如果你要赢
if you want to win,
你就得是佼佼者
then you got to be the shark.
而大鱼吃小鱼
And a shark's got to eat.
你们要我自噬吗
You're bibbing me?
鲍比  怎么了
Bobby, what is it?
他们让医生吃掉了他自己
He's making the doctor eat himself.
他们抓到他了
They got him.
迪恩  那儿至少有四个利维坦
Dean, there are at least four Leviathans out there.
我们连一个都弄不死
We don't even know how to kill one.
要是我们就从正门进去
Well, it'll be quite a shock
一定吓掉他们大牙  是吧
when we walk in through the front door, won't it?
好吧  狗娘养的
Okay, sons of bitches.
看看你们到底想干嘛
See what you're up to now.
鲍比  快
Bobby! Come on!
快走
Go! Go!
鲍比  给你帽子
Hey, Bobby, your hat.
天啊  鲍比
Oh, god. Bobby?!
鲍比
Bobby?!
(如今)
鲍比  鲍比
Bobby? Bobby?
坚持住
Hold on.
-萨姆  他死了吗  -我还在确认
- Sam, is he dead? - I'm checking.
他到底死了没
Is he dead?!
开你的车吧  迪恩  鲍比
Just drive, Dean! Bobby?
你得把情况告诉我  萨姆
You got to talk to me, Sam!
好了  他还有呼吸和脉搏
All right, he's breathing. There's a pulse.
扶他坐起来  帮他止血
Keep him upright. Stop the bleeding.
我又不是白痴  迪恩
I'm not an idiot, Dean.
我知道怎么给头部中弹的人做急救
I know first aid for a friggin' bullet to the head.
-最近的急救中心在哪  -挺住  挺住
- I need the nearest trauma center. - Hold on. Hold on.
把地址告诉我
What's the address?!
鲍比  你给我挺住
All right, Bobby, hang in there.
[邪恶力量 第7季第10集]
鲍比  坚持住啊
Bobby? Just hold on.
看来我们找到菲尔了
Well, I guess we found Phil.
等等
Wait a minute.
这里感觉不对劲
Something's not right here.
可不是嘛  鲍比  树上吊着个死人呢
Yeah, no kidding, Bobby. There's a corpse in a tree.
我感到了不祥之兆
Something bad's about to happen.
是啊  鲍比  危险无处不在
Yeah, well, danger's kind of on the W2, Bobby.
所以我们才要带枪过来
That's why we got the guns.
有可能不详已经发生了
Or something bad's happened already.
妈的
Balls.
跟我们说说到底怎么回事吧
Y-you want to tell us what's going on?
是啊  你的头怎么了
Yeah. What's going on with your head?
我头部中弹了
I got shot in it.
什么
You what?
鲍比  今天我们一直在一起
Bobby, we've been with you all day.
你要是中弹了  我们肯定知道
Yeah, I think we would have noticed if you took a bullet.
我不是在这儿中的枪
I didn't take one here.
而是在那边
I-I took one out there,
在现实世界
in the real world.
我没听懂
You lost us.
听着  鲍比  你要不要先坐下
Look, Bobby, you ... you want to sit down, seriously?
不  我有事要告诉你们
No, there's something I got to tell you.
我...
I ...
该死  我办不到
Damn it, I can't get at it.
没关系  慢慢想
Well, I-it's okay. Take your time.
我们等你
We're ... we're right here.
我不是指眼前的"你们"
No, no, not you you ...
而是真正的你们  现实中的你们
Real you, o-out there in ... in the waking world.
号码  号码
Numbers. Numbers.
哪里有纸
Where's paper?
我之前没有时间
I didn't have time before...
告诉你们他们的阴谋
...to tell you what they're cooking up.
你们需要知道
You need to know.
你怎么傻站着  不打算给我了吗  鲍比
Well, you just gonna stand there or hand it over, Bobby?
怎么回事
What the hell?
卡伦
Karen?
难道你希望是法拉·弗西特吗(美国女演员)
You were expecting Farrah Fawcett?
不  她不像你  来之前连电话都不打
No. She always calls first.
当时我就是怎么说的
That's what I said the first time this happened.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
给我
Gimme.
这里...
This...
这里一点都没变样
This is just like it was.
你真美
You're beautiful.
别光说好听的了  快过来
Quit sweet-talking and come here.
感觉我们好久没聊天了
I feel like we haven't talked in ages.
这我也深有体会
I know just how you feel.
听着
Listen ...
我有事想告诉你
I have something I want to say to you.
这次别找借口了  好吗
No excuses this time, okay?
坐下吧  鲍比
Just sit, Bobby.
我知道这是哪天晚上了
I know what night this is.
我记得这一幕
I remember this.
这事我想了很久
I've thought about this a lot.
-我真的想好了  -想好了
- I really sat with this. - Sat with this.
别逗我
Don't make fun of me.
怎么会呢
I wouldn't.
但现在我要...
But right now I got to ...
我不记得那晚有暴风雨
I don't remember a storm coming in the night this happened.
圣母玛丽啊  我脑子里还真是一锅粥
Mother Mary, I've got a messed-up fruitcake.
你说什么  鲍比
What, Bobby?
没什么
Nothing.
我得走了  对不起  亲爱的
I got to go. I'm sorry, darling.
鲍比  等等
Bobby, wait.
别走
Don't go.
最重要的诀窍
Number one trick
就是要装作轻车熟路  鲍比
is to act like you know what you're doing, Bobby.
鲁弗斯
Rufus?
怎么  现在不需要我的建议了吗
What, I can't give you advice now?
你突然就变得无所不知了吗
All of a sudden, you know everything?
我完全可以坐在车里  啥都不管
You know, I can always go wait in the car.
别  等等  我需要你帮忙
No, wait. I-I need your help ...
-非常需要  -不需要才怪
- bad. - Yeah, damn straight you do.
听我说  鲁弗斯  我就要死了
No, listen to me, Rufus. I'm gonna die.
整天出去捉鬼
Oh, now, that's a realistic view
难免搭上老命
of the mortality rate on a ghost hunt.
乖乖  红色警报
Whoa, Nellie, red line.
好了  小子  我们走
All right, baby boy, here we go.
别  鲁弗斯
No, Rufus ...
你到底进不进来  鲍比
Are you coming, Bobby?
我们没那么多时间让你耗
I mean, we're not getting any younger here.
这就来
Coming.
上帝会惩罚你的
God's gonna punish you.
你好  辛格先生
Hello, Mr. Singer.
你的时辰到了
Your time's up.
这么说你是来终结我的死神喽
So, you're my reaper, huh?
我听说过你们会在光天化日之下
You know, I've heard of you guys grabbing reapees
或是睡梦中取人性命
in broad daylight and in their sleep,
但我从没听说过死神还会出现在
but I never heard of a reaper showing up
别人的脑浆里
inside a guy's custard.
你昏迷了  是这么回事
You're in a coma, genius. This is what happens.
我爬进你的脑浆  把你捞出来了
I climb in your...custard and fish you out.
你以为可以甩掉我
Oh, you think you can lose me?
我想试试
I'm gonna try.
我还要四处赶场子  辛格
I've got places to be, Singer.
别浪费我的时间
Don't waste my time.
不浪白不浪
Might as well,
趁我还有时间可浪费
while I got it.
该来的总要来  你不过是在拖延罢了
You're prolonging the inevitable.
你逃不出我的掌心
I can find you anywhere!
这酒气冲天的老鼠洞也藏不住你
Even in this gin-soaked rat maze.
我只是说  看  这都没啥可比性
I'm just saying ... look, you can't really compare.
我现在都有点不认识你了
I don't even know you right now.
他俩差得太远了
There's not even a contest.
这要看你的标准
It depends on the criteria.
存活下来是唯一的标准  好吧
Survival is the only criteria, all right?
情势一触即发时
And when the crap hits the fan,
有没有格斗技巧没啥关系
it's not about who has skill.
有关系的是谁最凶恶
It's about who's the bigger badass.
鲍比  你能告诉萨姆
Bobby, will you please tell Sam
李连杰不是查克·诺里斯(美国电影演员)的对手吗
that Chuck Norris could kick Jet Li's ass?
顺便帮我拿瓶啤酒
Grab me a beer while you're in there?
鲍比
Bobby?
鲍比·辛格  你下来时最好已经收拾干净
Bobby Singer, you had better be washed up when you come down.
你好脏啊
You're filthy.
天啊  你怎么回事啊
God, what is wrong with you?
简直像是故意惹他生气
It's like you want him to get mad.
鲍比  接住
Bobby, heads up!
可怜的家伙
Whew! Poor thing.
结婚典礼上被甩  愤而自杀
Gets left at the altar, kills herself,
葬在这地穴里
and then gets buried in the crypt.
现在她追杀所有伤了女人心的负心汉
Now she's going after men who break their girls' hearts.
挺凄美的吧  我没说错吧
Poignant, am I wrong?
你为什么上气不接下气的
Why you out of breath?
你刚刚去慢跑了吗
Did you go for a jog up there, man?
我需要你的帮助  鲁弗斯
I need your help, Rufus.
对  显然的
Yeah, clearly.
不是  听我说
No, listen to me.
伙计  拿个喷火器过来
I want you to grab a torch, man.
我一打开她的棺材
As soon as I open up her coffin,
她肯定会立刻发起猛攻
showtime's coming pretty quick.
不是  你能不能听我说  你这混蛋
No. Will you listen to me, you son of a bitch?
有个死神要收走我
There's a damn reaper coming for me.
咱们每一个人都被死神追着索命呢  鲍比
There's a damn reaper coming for all of us, Bobby.
好了  咱们赶紧收拾掉这鬼魂吧
All right, let's put this damn ghost to bed.
我还要好好过普珥节(犹太教假期)呢
I got plans for Purim.
赶紧呼叫待命的神经外科医生
Page the neurosurgeon on call.
通知手术室让不紧急的病人先等等
Tell O.R. to put electives on hold.
七号台空下就将外伤二号病人转移过去
Move trauma 2 to bed 7 as soon as it's clean.
右额叶区有枪伤
Gunshot wound to the right frontal area.
没有发现其他外伤
No exit wound found.
能自主呼吸  呼吸频率18十分微弱
Breathing spontaneously. Respiratory rate 18 and shallow.
RTS指数120  血压90  60
RST at 120. B.P. 90 over 60.
格拉斯昏迷评分为5
GCS 5.
80克甘露醇30分钟静推
Push 80 grams of mannitol over 30.
-准备插管  -呼吸道通畅
- Prep for intubation. - Air entry clear to bases.
马上拿一个中央管来
Let's get a central line in here now.
怎么样了  能不能告诉我们...
What's happening? Please just tell us ...
让他们赶紧出去
Get them out of here.
抱歉  你们不能影响医生的工作
Sorry. You need to stay out of their way.
-那是我们的叔叔  -你们得出去
- That's our uncle. - You got to stay back.
-他们在干什么  -我们得先把他稳定下来
- What are they doing? - We need to get him stable.
好  你们会把子弹取出来吗
Okay, when are you gonna take the bullet out?
如果我们能让脑部的肿胀消退
If we can get the swelling down,
如果子弹在我们能触及的地方  如果...
if it's in a place we can get to, if ...
如果他还能活到那时
If he even lives that long.
算我没说  我得继续了
Forget it. I got to keep moving.
负心汉
Heartbreaker.
再10分钟静推30克甘露醇
Push 30 more of mannitol over 10.
做血细胞计数  挂上500毫升的生理盐水
CBC and 'lytes. Bolus him with 500 saline.
两分钟前生命指数还稳定
The vitals were stable two minutes ago.
可他现在不行了
Well, he's crashing now.
我要伤碎你的心
I'll break your heart.
鲍比
Bobby...
好了  你没事吧  说话啊
Come on. You okay? Say something.
小心
Look out!
血压130  90
Blood pressure 130 over 90.
好了  鲁弗斯  我要你
Okay, Rufus, I need you ...
混蛋
Oh, balls.
这是那次你险些送命的活
This would be the one job you damn near got yourself killed on.
就算要我背着你  你也得帮帮我
Well, you're gonna be useful, even if I have to carry you.
他暂时稳定下来了
He's, uh, stable for the moment.
只能等待观察了
Just have to see.
鲁弗斯
Rufus...
见鬼你哪去了
Where the hell did you go?
叫你呢  小孩
Yeah, you! You, kid!
你怎么像个小白兔似地
Hey, what are you making like a white rabbit
到处出现呢  你这小鬼头
all over the place for, you grubby little ...
别再突然蹦出来吓人了  小孩
Enough with the jump scares, kid.
谁在追你啊
Who are you running from?
等等  我认识你
Wait a minute. I know you.
你以为我死了吗
Did you think I was dead?
回头给我打电话  好吗
Call me, all right?
别再为我哭哭啼啼了  鲍比
Don't sit shiva for me yet, Bobby.
你被那疯新娘打昏后
Listen, after bridezilla took you out,
你还记得你告诉过我  你的濒死经历吗
do you remember what you told me about your near-death experience?
我还什么都没告诉你呢
I haven't told you nothing yet.
但你既然提到了
But now that you mention it,
我很确定我差点就过去了
pretty sure I almost crossed over.
你都看见什么了
And what did you see?
我看见什么了  伙计你干嘛这么激动啊
What did I see? What are you so riled up about, paco?
好了  好啦
All right, all right.
我看见一个门厅  铺着格子地毯
I saw a hallway, uh, plaid carpet,
-还有我小时候住的楼  -然后呢
- uh, the apartment building from when I was a kid. - And?
然后我想跑出来
And I wanted out.
我才不要死在那破格子地摊上呢
I'm not dying on no damn plaid carpet.
-不必  多谢美意  -那么你是怎么做的
- No, thank you. - So, what did you do?
这很明显啊  鲍比  不能犯傻
Well, obviously, Bobby, not being stupid,
我开始找出口
I started looking for the damn exit door.
我发誓这就是他们说的
Y-you know, I swear that's what they mean
你的生活片段从你眼前闪过
about your life flashing before your eyes,
因为我每次打开一扇门
'cause every time I opened the door,
里面都是我的一段记忆
there was another chapter inside,
那些好事  坏事  还有那些血腥的事
the good, the bad, the bloody.
那么你是怎么跑出来的
So, how did you get out?
显然要找到正确的门啊
Found the right door, obviously.
你怎么找到的
Well, how did you find it?
很简答  我往深处走
Oh, simple ... I went deep.
深处  你是说很久远的记忆吗
Deep. Like old?
不  深处是像
No, deep like...
那些你不想再回想起的破事
crap you do not want to think about.
把它埋在心底  用其他的破事掩埋它
So you bury it, you shove other crap over it,
之后你再也不去想它  再也不想
And you don't go there, ever.
你是说
So, you're telling me
出去的路  是走过你最不堪回首的记忆吗
that the way out was through your worst memory?
那是一扇很重要的门  鲍比
It's an important door, Bobby.
好  真很好
Okay, this is good.
你这么追问不休是干嘛呀
What the hell are you going on about, anyway?
这个
This.
我得找到正确的门把这东西送到萨姆和迪恩手里
I got to find the right door to get this to Sam and Dean.
我现在处于昏迷状态  鲁弗斯
I'm in a coma, Rufus, right now.
别扯了
Get out.
我的大脑袋中弹了  鲁弗斯
I got shot in the dunce cap, Rufus.
我要死了
I'm ... I'm dying.
你确定吗
You sure?
不幸的是我确定
Unfortunately.
我他妈勒个去
I'll be a prima ballerina.
等等  鲍比  你是想说
Wait, wait, Bobby are you trying to tell me
我只是你一段比较美好的记忆吗
I'm just one of your better memories?
我骗你做什么啊
Would I make this up?
-好了  我得走了  -什么
- Okay. I got to go. - What?
-你得跟我一起走  鲁弗斯  -什么
- You're coming with me, Rufus. - What?
我需要一个搭档
I need my partner on this.
求你了
Please.
想想你最不堪的记忆
Aim for your worst memory.
集中注意力想
Think. Focus.
懂了吗  最差的
You got it? The worst, okay?
那多了去了
I got a metric ton of worst.
挑一件
Just take a shot.
对了  那个杀人新娘
By the way, killer bride ...
她为什么喊你负心汉
How come she call you a heartbreaker, anyway?
如果说我还见过一个顾家的男人  就是你了
I mean, you a family man if I ever saw one.
多谢帮我缩小范围
Thanks for narrowing things down.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe you.
我恨你
I hate you.
一切都是谎言
Everything's a lie.
我们全部的生活
Our whole life...
我们的誓言
Our vows...
一切的一切
Everything.
你知道我想要孩子
You knew I wanted kids.
为什么你就不能
Why didn't you just...
坐下来然后告诉我
sit me down and say...
我不明白
I don't understand.
你是个好男人
You're a good man.
你也会是个好爸爸
You'd be a good dad.
那些话是什么意思
What does that even mean,
你碰什么毁什么
You break everything you touch?!
那算什么借口
What kind of excuse is that?!
离我远点
Just stay away from me!
你伤透了我的心  鲍比
You broke my heart, Bobby!
你开心了吗
You happy?
滚开
Just go away!
我想告诉你  对不起
Just so you know... I'm sorry.
我一直都很愧疚
I never stopped being sorry.
鲍比  我以为你想要一窝孩子呢
Bobby, I thought you'd want a gang of rugrats.
这事多久以后...
So, how long after this ...
她就被附身了吗
Did she get possessed?
三天后
Three days.
这是我最后悔的一件事
Biggest regret of my life, this fight.
你会以为我刺死她是最后悔的
You'd think it was when I had to stab her to death,
但并非如此
but...no.
一直以来
All through that...
我都想着
I was thinking
我们都没机会言归于好
we never got to get past this.
若早知当初
If I'd have known,
我就会都说些她爱听的
I'd have said anything she wanted to hear.
鲍比
Bobby?
试试那个门
Try the door.
快
Now.
谢谢  鲁弗斯
Thanks, Rufus.
见鬼
Balls.
这是那一年
What year is this?
89年吗
'89-ish?
这有关系吗
What's it matter?
我还不是困在这该死的地方
I'm still stuck in eternal friggin' sunshine.
不  我只是觉得
No, I was just thinking, man...
你看起来挺不错
you look pretty good there.
肯定没喝高
Must have drank less.
鲍比  我们这是去哪儿
Hey, Bobby, where are we going?
迪恩  这看起来像哪儿
Well, Dean, where's it look like?
爸爸说我应该练双筒枪了
Dad says I'm supposed to practice with the double-barrel.
今天我们不练枪  过去
Well, we're gonna skip the guns today. Here.
今天
Today...
你就好好扔这个球
You're gonna throw a ball around,
就像个普通的鼻涕虫那样
just like a regular snot-nosed little jerk.
作为一个宁可伤老婆心
You know, for a guy who'd rather break his wife's heart
也不跟她生娃娃的人
than give her a baby,
当起保姆来还真不赖
you make a hell of a nanny.
闭嘴  鲁弗斯
Shut up, Rufus.
我们该去找下一扇门了
We need another door.
走吧
Let's go.
说真的  鲍比  你是怎么想的
Seriously, though, Bobby, how come ...
别问了  鲁弗斯
Dog with a bone, Rufus.
不  我真的想知道
No, I really want to know, man.
为什么不要孩子
Why no kids?
没那么复杂
Ain't that deep.
我老爸是个恶棍酒鬼
Dad was a mean drunk.
我怕我跟他一样
I figured I'd be just like him.
你了解我的  我说对了
And, hey, look ... I was right.
没必要把这传下去
No sense passing on the legacy.
你对你自己太严苛了
Man, you're too hard on yourself.
你至多就是脾气差的酒鬼
You're more of a cranky drunk.
你知道你又翻白眼  又冲我发火
You do know that whatever you're trying to avoid
就是想回避那个
with the eye rolls and the grump-a-lumping ...
你最该去的地方
that's exactly where you need to go.
-我没回避什么  -是啊
- I ain't avoiding nothing. - Yeah, sure.
滚你的  鲁弗斯
Get off my ass, rufus.
鲍比  我这不是在帮你吗
Hey, Bobby, I'm trying to help you here, okay?
你要从这儿出去
You want to get out of here,
还是想死
or you want to die?
我在努力了
I'm trying.
我要怎么知道我不想让我知道什么
How am I supposed to know what I don't want me to know?
听着
Hey, look.
王子殿下决定大驾光临来吃宵夜了
The crown prince decided to drop by for a late bite.
他刚刚在洗手
Oh, he ... he was just washing up.
那  谁来念祷文呢
So, w-who would like to say grace?
去他妈的祷文  把饼干递给我
Hell with grace. Pass me the biscuits.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你他妈怎么回事
What is the matter with you?
我不是故意的  对不起
I don't know. I'm sorry.
你碰什么毁什么
You break everything you touch!
就让我们好好吃晚饭吧
Let's just have a nice supper.
好好吃饭
A nice supper?
去你的晚饭
There's your nice supper.
我在这家里得不到尊重
I get no respect in this house.
怎么了
What?
你现在可别跟我说
Now, you can't tell me
这记忆差得不够进去一探究竟的
that wasn't gnarly enough to go spelunking in.
每个周二都是如此
That was any given Tuesday night.
相信我  没什么特别的
Believe me ... it was nothing special.
不  不  不  你怕了
No, no, no. You're scared.
我没有
No, I ain't.
我只知道我们进错地方了  鲁弗斯
I just know we're in the wrong place, Rufus.
你
You ...
好吧  鲍比  你没时间了
Okay, Bobby, you don't have time.
这可不是变天了  你懂的
That sound was not the weather, and you know it.
我们不能再这么一扇一扇门的找了
We can't keep bopping through your greatest hits forever.
死神马上就来了
That reaper's gonna catch up.
如果有办法阻止他还好
I mean, if there was some way to stop the damn thing...
但那可是死神  鲍比  你完蛋了
But it's a reaper, Bobby. You're screwed.
我知道我们该干嘛
I know what we're gonna do.
什么
What?
我们要阻止那该死的死神
We're gonna stop the damn reaper.
我们就什么也干不了了吗
So, there's nothing else we can do?
对不起  我们只能等了
I'm sorry. We just have to wait.
-还得看肿胀能不能消  -等多久
- We'll see if the swelling goes down. - How long?
这样的情况  很难说
It's hard to say in cases like this.
他能坚持到现在  总是好事吧
Well, he's lasted this long. That's something, right?
是的
Well, yes.
听着  子弹没有碎掉
Listen ... the bullet didn't shatter.
大脑只有一个半球受损
Only one hemisphere of his brain was injured.
这都是好事
These are all positive things.
但  我不想给你们虚幻的希望
But...I don't want to give you false hope here.
他陷入深度昏迷
He's far from out of the woods.
多数情况下  这样的病例
Most of the time, cases like this...
都救不活了
They die.
现在就看他自己了
Right now it comes down to him.
有进一步消息我会告诉你的
I'll keep you updated.
打扰
Excuse me.
抱歉打扰你们
Sorry to interrupt.
你们谁是罗伯特·辛格的近亲吗
Is one of you Robert Singer's next of kin?
我们知道你们现在很紧张
We know this is a stressful time.
好了  无意冒犯  但废话就省了吧
Yeah, okay. No offense ... you can skip the garnish.
是他的保险失效了  还是咋的
What, did his insurance lapse, or what?
很抱歉要问你
We're sorry to ask,
但  你叔叔有没有表明
but, um, did your uncle ever make his wishes known
关于器官捐献的意愿
i-in regards to organ donation?
器官只在很短的时间段内可用
Organs are only viable for a very limited window ...
"可用"
"Viable"?
我们只是希望能从不幸中孕育福音
We're just hoping some good can come of this tragic ...
听我说  我只说一次
Listen to me. I'm gonna say this once.
他不会死  只是一枚子弹而已
He's not gonna die. It's one bullet.
他不会有事  因为他向来如此
He's gonna be fine because he's always fine.
我很抱歉
I apologize.
你干嘛一副他已经死了的腔调跟我说话
Why are you talking to me like he's gonna die, huh?
我干我该干的  你也是
I do my job! Do your jobs!
-救活他  -当然  他们在尽全力抢救
- Save him! - Of course they're doing everything they can.
给哥滚
Walk away from me.
马上
Now!
(汉默顿地区医院)
迪克  我知道你在里面
Dick! I know you're in there.
出来你个混蛋
Come on out, you dick.
怎么  你来了结未完成的工作吗
What, did you come here to finish the job?
是这样吗  来啊
Yeah? Well, come on.
就在这儿  就现在
Right here, right now,
光天化日  你我对决  来吧迪克·罗曼
out in the open, you and me, Dick Roman.
瞧见没
See?
扮成知名人士也不都是好事
Deciding to jump a famous guy ain't all upside.
你现在就可以杀了我  不过会被传到网上
You can kill me right now ... you want to see it online.
你还是去看看你的朋友吧
Maybe you should go check on that friend of yours.
他现在肯定不那么闹腾了
He can't be feeling too frisky right about now.
我可是神枪手
I'm a very good shot.
我们会来找你的
We're coming for you,
不只是要伤到你  而是要杀了你
and not just to hurt you ... to kill you.
懂吗
You understand me?
得了  迪恩  我死不了
Come on, Dean. I can't be killed.
那就让你求死不得
You're gonna wish you could, then.
大言不惭
That's some conviction.
你还真是揣着一肚子劲儿啊
You'd really crush it on the motivational circuit.
笑成这样  不是为了掩饰你害怕
You're either laughing because you're scared
就是脑子缺弦
or you're laughing because you're stupid.
回见  迪克
I'll see you soon, Dick.
在一本钦定本圣经里
It's in an old King James Bible.
我们到底要做什么  鲍比
So, what exactly are we doing now, Bobby?
准确地说  你说得对
Well, technically, you're correct.
我们不能阻止一个死神  至少不能永远阻止
You can't stop a reaper, not permanently.
那只有他们老大才办得到
Only their boss can do that,
我们可不想把他扯进来
and we don't want him involved.
总算不是无米之炊了
Now we're cooking with gas.
那是什么
What is that?
萨姆和迪恩
Well, Sam and Dean
跟这帮怂货打过两三次照面了
have run up against these suckers a couple, three times.
所以我学了几招
Picked up a few tricks ...
至少能拖住他们一会儿了
enough to slow them down a hair, at least.
好吧  我们施咒吧
All right. Let's work some mojo.
-那家伙想干嘛  -没事
- What did that guy want? - Uh, nothing.
就是保险的破事
Just some insurance mook.
迪克·罗曼刚刚在外面
Dick Roman was out there.
什么  发生什么事了
What? What happened?
没事...暂时没事
Nothing...For now.
就是场瞪眼比赛罢了
It was just a friggin' staring contest.
差不多就是这样
That was about it.
有什么新情况
What's the update?
肿胀消退了一点
The swelling's down a little.
他们不再给他打镇静剂了
They took him off sedation.
因为他开始抵抗给他插的管子
Apparently, he ... he started fighting his tube.
所以他们就把管子拔出来了  他现在时自主呼吸
So they pulled them out, and he's breathing on his own.
这是好事吧  是不是
That's good, right? Is that good?
是啊  医生说是最佳情况了
Yeah. Well, doctor said best-case scenario.
好啊  那他们什么时候取出子弹
All right, so when they gonna take the bullet out?
迪恩  他们根本
Dean, t-they're not even ...
他们根本没那个打算  暂时没有
they're not even gonna try that, not yet.
这什么意思
What does that mean?
说是"磨损"
The word's "abrading," I think.
说人话
English.
要切除死去的脑组织
Cutting out the dead brain tissue.
那还得医生认为值得冒险
That's if the doctor even thinks it's worth the risk.
能跟你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you?
怎么了  谈什么
What? Talk about what?
你懂的
You know what.
-不  我们不谈这个  -我们必须谈
- No, we're not gonna have that conversation. - Oh, we need to.
-他不会死的  -这难说
- He's not gonna die. - He might.
-萨姆  -迪恩  听我说
- Sam. - Dean, listen ...
我们得做好准备
we need to brace ourselves.
-为什么  -因为这是来真的
- Why? - Because it's real.
你想做什么
What do you want to do?
你想我们抱抱
You want to hug and ...
说什么爸爸死的时候我们也撑过去了吗
and say we made it through it when dad died?
我们经历了太多了
We've been through enough.
我们还需要金矿石  铁杉和权杖
We still need gold ore, hemlock, and mace.
那就是些普通的东西喽
Mm. So, pretty basic, then, huh?
没有  事实上  我们没练习开枪
No, we didn't shoot rifles, as a matter of fact.
我们扔球玩来着
We threw a ball around.
他是个孩子  约翰  他们都是
He's a kid, John. They both are.
他们有权这么做
They're entitled.
对  我知道我不是他们的爹
Yeah, I know I ain't their dad.
搞毛啊
What the hell?
[咒语]
妙招啊
Cute.
我得承认
Got to admit ...
这还是第一次有人在昏迷中对我使这招呢
first time anyone's pulled one on me while actually unconscious.
随便坐
Well, get comfy.
别急着溜
Not so fast.
是吗
Yeah?
抱歉  还有事
Sorry. Other business.
我是想帮你  鲍比
I'm trying to help you, Bobby.
你要死了
You're going to die.
你以为你把我定在这儿就能阻止得了吗
Think you can stop it by pinning me like a bug?
那又如何
Well ...
你都看见了  黑暗降临
You've seen the dark coming ...
人们消失  一片空白
people disappearing, things going blank.
四下看看
Look around.
一个细胞接着一个细胞
Cell by cell...
子弹在蚕食你的大脑
that bullet's killing your brain.
你就要无处可逃了
You're running out of places to hide.
你要知道  这个陷阱撑不了很久
So, understand ... this trap won't hold forever
因为这间屋子撑不下去
because this room won't hold
因为你要死了
because you are going to die.
那是你的看法
You think.
跟我走吧
Come with me.
就此了结
Be done.
你该休息了
You've earned it.
不然就抗争
Or fight me.
留下
Stay here.
你知道会怎样
And you know the drill.
不好说啊  鲍比
I don't know, Bobby.
你真想困在这儿
I mean, you really want to get stuck,
变成鬼魂吗
turn into some ghost?
我知道我在做什么  鲁弗斯
I know what I'm doing, Rufus.
是啊  是啊  你在想你能帮助那俩小子
Yeah, yeah, you're thinking you can help those boys.
但是你遇见几个头脑正常的鬼魂
But how many sprits you meet in their right mind?
总会有个猎人灭了你的
Some hunter's gonna cut you down.
你到底哪边的
Whose side are you on?
鲍比
Bobby...
你出过力了
You've helped.
你的生命渺小而平凡
You got handed a small, unremarkable life,
你却有所作为
and you did something with it.
大部分你这样的男人都一边看着
Most men like you die of liver disease,
《巴尼·米勒》的重播  死于肝病
watching "Barney Miller" reruns.
你已经尽力了
You've done enough.
相信我
Believe me.
-我不在乎  -为什么
- I don't care. - Why?
因为他们是我的孩子
Because they're my boys.
好吧
All right.
要想出去  只能走到底
The only way out is through.
带路吧
So lead the way.
能再见到你真好  老伙计
Nice seeing you again, old friend.
谢谢你陪我聊天
Thanks for the chat.
没事的
It's fine.
一会儿就收拾好了
It'll just take a second.
你就那么坐着
You just gonna sit there?
去找把扫帚什么的
Get a broom or somethin'.
你知道他为什么这样
You know why he's like that?
就因为你总是顺着他
Because you let him do whatever he wants.
没事的  你瞧  我就收拾好了
It's okay. See? I'm almost done.
你就放松一下  再喝一杯吧
You just relax a-and have another drink.
别对我指手画脚
Don't tell me what to do.
不  等等
No. Wait.
等等
Wait.
不要
I... no!
你为什么总挑他的刺
Why do you always provoke him?
因为他是个坏孩子
Because he's a bad kid ...
就因为这个
That's why.
真他妈的放屁
Well, that's a load of crap.
你有什么资格说这话
Who the hell were you to say?
我是你老子
I'm your father.
你要对我尊敬点
And you show your father respect.
你值得我尊敬再说  你个醉鬼恶霸
The day he deserves it, you drunken bully.
打女人  打孩子
Punching women and kids ...
你们那个年代这样就叫为人父吗
Is that what they call fatherhood in your day?
你就是欠打  相信我
Oh, you deserved it. Believe me.
你就是不知好歹
You were nothing but ungrateful.
我是个孩子
I was a kid!
孩子哪知道好歹
Kids ain't supposed to be grateful!
他们就是吃你的还伤你心
They're supposed to eat your food and break your heart,
你这自私的混球
you selfish dick!
你死了我还那么害怕
You died, and I was still so afraid
怕我会变成你  结果我自己都没有孩子
I'd turn into you I never even had kids of my own.
那正好
Good.
反正你碰什么毁什么
You break everything you touch.
命运弄人
Well, as fate would have it,
我收养了两个男孩  他们都长大成材
I adopted two boys, and they grew up great.
成了英雄
They grew up heroes.
所以你他妈去死吧
So you can go to hell!
病床摇起准备转移
Keep the head of the bed up for transport.
静脉注射可以暂停  保持静脉通畅即可
I.V. can run off the pump. Just run a TKVO.
-我们得等呼吸机  -等等
- We'll have to wait for respiratory. - Wait, wait, wait, wait.
-怎么回事  -他出现有反应的迹象
- What's happening? - He's showing signs of responsiveness.
我们要送他去手术
We're taking him up for surgery.
如果你们想见他  就赶快去
If you want to see him, I'd squeeze in there quick.
对不起  我说  我很抱歉
I'm sorry. I said that I'm ... I'm sorry.
是啊  是啊  你总是那么说
Yeah, yeah, you say that every time.
求你停手吧
Please just stop.
不  这次  你给我听着
No! This time, you listen!
住手
Stop it.
你闹什么呢
You're kidding, right?
要用这东西你还不够爷们
You're not half enough man to use that thing.
让大人先把事说完
You leave the adults to sort this out...
我待会儿再来收拾你
And I will deal with you later.
鲍比  快走吧
Ohh! Aah! Bobby, just go.
按他说的做
Do what he says.
-快走  -不  别碰她
- Just go. No. - Leave her alone.
鲍比  你做了什么啊
Bobby, what did you do?
上帝会惩罚你的
God is gonna punish you.
你做了你必须做的
You did what you had to do.
你就是这时明白
This is where you learn that...
被救的人几乎从不说谢谢
they pretty much never say thanks when you save 'em.
快去找把铲子
Now go get a shovel.
把他埋在木棚后面
Bury the old man out behind the woodshed.
我还没见过连脑子中弹都遗传的呢
You got the only genetic case of bullet in the brain I've ever seen.
别这么急  辛格
Not so fast, Singer.
抱歉  我们得走了
Sorry. We need to get moving.
-好  -好吧
- Right. - Yeah.
鲍比
Bobby, um...
只想说  谢谢你
...just...thanks...
为我们做的一切
...for everything.
-好了  请后退  -好
- All right. Please step back. - Yeah.
等等  等等  停下  他睁眼了
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. Stop. His eyes are open.
鲍比
Bobby?
什么
What ...
别说话  别说话
Don't talk. Don't talk.
笔  给  给你
A pen ... I ... here. Here, here, here.
怎么了
What is it?
小混球
Idjits.
鲍比
Bobby?
呼叫  来外伤室
Call a code ... trauma room.
你在酿酒啊
You microbrewing in there, or what?
快点  我们还有很多查克·诺里斯电影要看呢
Come on ... we got a lot of Chuck Norris to get through.
动作麻利点
Let's go.
漂亮啊  居然醒过来了
Nice move, waking up like that.
有动力才有一切
Motivation's a mother.
你明白外面为什么一片漆黑吧
You know why it's dark out there, don't you?
这栋房子  是你最后的孤岛
This house ... it's your last island,
其他的一切都被子弹抹去了
everything else melted by that bullet ...
消失了
gone.
这是你最后的机会  跟我走  往前看
This is your last chance to come with me and move on.
这是为你自己好  鲍比  放手吧
For your own good, Bobby, let go.
没有你他们也能行
They'll be okay without you.
最后的记忆了吗
Last memory, huh?
幸好我把最好的留到最后
Glad I saved the best for last.
靠边闪  二逼青年  对你老哥尊敬点
All right, scoot, jerkface. Show your elders some respect.
你闪吧  讨厌
You scoot, ass-hat.
你加甘草汁了吗
Did we get licorice?
没  没加甘草汁
No, we did not get licorice.
这是好零食  甘草汁多恶心啊
We got good snacks. Licorice is disgusting.
抱歉  我不太理解
I'm sorry. I didn't quite understand that,
花生酱加香蕉三文治你倒觉得美味
uh, Mr. Peanut-butter-and-banana sandwiches?
你知道吗  我就是挺我的三文治
You know what? I stand by that sandwich.
没人喜欢甘草汁  味同泥土
Nobody likes licorice. I-it's ... it's made of dirt.
那是经典的电影零食
It is a classic movie food.
与爆米花并列
It's right up there with popcorn.
-爆米花  不是吧  -没错
- Popcorn? Really? - Yes.
你真是疯了
You're out of your mind.
怎么了  简直是口嚼天堂
What ... it's like little chewy pieces of heaven.
这话娘们说还差不多
Oh, chewy pieces of heaven if you're a girl.
怎么样  鲍比
Well, Bobby?
是走是留  你怎么打算
Stay or go ... what's it gonna be?